KYUSHU BLOCK- FUKUOKA BASE
We hereby declare in this
place the revival of Japan...
我々は ここに正当なる独立主権国家
as a legitimate independent
and sovereign nation!
日本の再興を宣言する！
Atsushi Sawasaki, leader of the group
which has occupied Fukuoka base,
フクオカ基地を占拠した
グループの中心人物 澤崎敦は
was Chief Cabinet Secretary
in the old Japanese government...
旧日本政府 第２次枢木政権で
官房長官を務めていた男です
and the number two man
under Prime Minister Kururugi.
He fled to the Chinese Federation after the war,
戦後 中華連邦に亡命していましたが
but it is thought he's made this move...
ゼロの活動に伴う
昨今の内情不安につけ込み
as a result of recent civil
unrest caused by Zero's actions.
行動を起こしたものと思われます
なお 黒の騎士団が関与しているかは
調査中ですが
Furthermore, whether the Black Knights are
connected with this is still under investigation...
先日のレーダー基地…
関係ねえって
We're not part of it!
キョウトは なんと言ってるんだ？
What's Kyoto say about it?
They apparently had no idea this was coming.
ああ 知らなかったようです
They were just sent a unilateral notice
regarding Sakuradite mining rights.
サクラダイトの採掘権に関してのみ
一方的に通告してきたと
Zero, what should we do?
ゼロ　私達どうすれば？
夢見てた夢
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
果て無き遠く
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
等身大 音をたてて
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
キレイに　片方だけ
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
この手に落ちた
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
頭身台 爪をたてて
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
THE BATTLE FOR KYUSHU
澤崎のグループは
Sawasaki's group was operating in conjunction
with a terrorist organization in Kyushu.
キュウシュウブロック内の
テロリスト組織と協力し
ホンシュウ シコクブロックとの
陸上交通網を寸断したあと
After cutting mainland access
from Honshu and Shikoku,
中華連邦両島軍管区の支援を受け
and with the support of the Chinese
Federation's Liaodong military district forces...
フクオカ ナガサキ オオイタを中心に
占領範囲を広げています
they're securing more and more territory
around Fukuoka, Nagasaki, and Oita.
中華連邦のツァオ将軍によると
これは あくまで人道支援であり
According to General Tsao
of the Chinese Federation,
this is essentially humanitarian support and not
in contravention to the Manila Conference or...
マニラ会議とメルボルンで…
どう？　スザク君の様子は？
So, how's Suzaku doing?
それが作戦なら従うと
Saying he'll do whatever the mission demands.
あっそ
I see.
あの… それでシュナイゼル殿下は？
Um, what about Prince Schneizel?
トウキョウ租界
In the Tokyo Settlement. This happened
right after the incident with Suzaku, right?
スザク君の問題に続いて これでしょ？
あるじ不在だけど
これをクリアしなきゃ
Our master may be away,
but unless we solve this problem,
ゲフィオンディスターバー対策は
取れないからねぇ
we'll have no way to counter
the Gefjun Disturber.
自分には
あなたの騎士たる資格がありません
I'm not qualified to be your knight.
命令違反の事なら シュナイゼル兄様が
If it's about your disobeying orders,
my brother Schneizel said...
非常時の事であり
責を問う必要はないと…
it was an unusual situation and that
you don't have to be blamed for it.
自分を許せないんです　だから…
I can't forgive myself.
So, please...
重荷だったでしょうか？
騎士に任じた事
Has being a knight become a burden for you?
いいえ　感謝しています
No, I'm grateful for it.
だったら…
Then...
思い出してしまったんです
I've remembered.
え？
自分は… 父を殺したんです
I... I killed my own father.
え？
なのに罰せられる事もなく
のうのうと生きている
Even so, I was never punished.
I just lived on like nothing happened.
そしてまた こうして守られて
And once again,
I'm being protected!
殉職者やイレヴンの人達を横目に
１人だけ…
While others die in duty and Elevens
suffer on the side, I get special treatment!
そんな自分に こんな資格は…
A person like me doesn't deserve this!
資格なんて… 私だって…
I don't deserve it, either...
コーネリア殿下 損害が大き過ぎます
Princess Cornelia,
we're taking too many losses!
この天候では空も使えませんし
This weather's preventing
us from using our air power!
上陸作戦は天候が安定してからかと
We'll have to delay the landing
operation until the weather calms down.
ん…
ぎょう倖ですなぁ 暴風雨とは
How fortunate for us we have this storm.
今のうちにキュウシュウをまとめられる
We should use this chance to
solidify our hold on Kyushu.
ツァオ将軍　天が味方している
You see, Gen. Tsao? Heaven is on our side.
We're going to win this battle.
勝ちますよ　この戦は
戒厳令は必要ないよ
市民を不安にさせるだけだからねぇ
There's no need for martial law.
That will only upset people.
ＥＵのガンドルフィ外相に親書を
Send a personal dispatch to
E.U. Foreign Minister Gandolphi.
ああ それと
カンボジアのトロモ機関に繋いで
Oh, and you, contact the
Tromo Institute in Cambodia.
シュナイゼル殿下 トロモは扱いが…
Prince Schneizel, using Tromo...
宰相閣下
Prime Minister!
やあユフィ　どうしたんだい？
Ah, Euphy. Is something wrong?
何かお手伝いできる事はありませんか？
Is there anything I can do to help?
エリア11の副総督として わたくしも…
I am sub-viceroy of Area 11,
so I should be helping.
ありがとう　その気持ちだけで十分だ
Thank you.
Just your willingness to help is enough.
でも…
But...
副総督には何もさせるなと
総督のご命令です
The viceroy ordered that you not be
made to do anything in this matter.
お姉様？
She did? Just because I chose
my knight without her consent...
いくら勝手に
騎士を決めたからといって…
ああ いえ　それは違います
Oh, no. That's not correct.
Even I think the Kururugi matter is...
枢木の件は私も…
分かってあげなよ　ユフィ
Please understand, Euphy.
こんな時だから
コーネリアにも余裕がないんだよ
Cornelia can't take any chances in this situation.
それは…
You mean...
ダールトン さっきの件だけど
私の知り合いがルートを持っている
Darlton, concerning that matter before,
I know someone who has a way in with them.
頼んでみるよ
Ask him.
分かりました
Yes, Your Highness.
こ～んなに頑張って準備してるのに
やっぱり中止かな？　学園祭
After all our hard work preparing for it,
I guess the school festival will be canceled.
そんな問題じゃないっしょ　戦争だよ？
That's hardly the problem.
We're at war, right?
戦争って…
War?
間に亡命政権を挟んでいるだけで
They may be using the
government in exile as a fig leaf,
これは中華連邦との戦争だって
but this is a war with
the Chinese Federation!
そんなぁ…
It can't be...
ニーナ
Nina, what about the outdoor booths we were
planning to borrow from the art museum?
美術館から借りる予定の屋外ブースは？
あっ 今日 手続きに
Oh, we were going to formalize it today.
できれば そのあと
科学庁に寄りたいんだけど…
If you could, I'd like you to drop into
the science department later on...
それって… 例のプレゼント？
Are you talking about that... present... of yours?
へ？
Huh?
プレゼントって？
What present?
欲しい物があって
頼んだら くれるってロイド先生が…
Prof. Lloyd said I should ask him
if there was something I wanted.
ロイド？　あの女ったらし！
LLOYD?! That playboy?!
いいから あんたは作業を進めて
Enough. You keep at your work.
んな事いっても
３人分やってんだよ？
Easy for you to say,
but this is work for three people!
スザクは軍隊 カレンは病院
Suzaku in the army, Kallen's hospitalized,
and the remaining idiot's nowhere to be found.
残ったバカは雲隠れ
あ～ああ
なんか変わっちまったよなぁ
ルルーシュの奴
Something's really weird about Lelouch lately.
驚きました　まだ混乱しています
ルルが あのゼロだなんて
I was so shocked.
I'm still so upset about it.
How can Lulu be Zero?!
まだ誰にも言ってません
I still haven't told anyone.
ルルに会って直接確かめたいから
I want to meet Lulu
first and ask him directly.
あれは私が書いた物なの？
Did I really write that?
どうして私は忘れているの？
Why did I forget?
ナナちゃんのお兄さんの　ゼロの事…
That Nunna's big brother is Zero...
Z-01
Z-01 float attachment, contact.
フロートアタッチメント コンタクト
制御ライン確立
Control line, established.
Avionics, all systems, on-line.
ファビオニクス…
大したものね
フロートシミュレートもトップクラスよ
That's really amazing.
You rated as top class on the float simulator.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
ねえ
どうして騎士をやめようと思ったの？
Tell me... Why did you want
to give up being a knight?
それは…
Well...
ユーフェミア皇女殿下は
こんな僕でも認めてくれたんです
Princess Euphemia still approves
of me, even as I am now.
だから 迷惑をかけると
So, If I cause her any trouble...
あの人が
自分自身を嫌ってしまいそうな…
I just had a feeling she would
end up hating me herself.
そんな気がして…
お飾りの副総督
A figurehead sub-viceroy...
それは最初から分かってたし
I realized that's what I was from the start.
でも やれる事を
頑張ろうと思ったのに…
But I thought I could try hard
and show them what I could do.
ごめんなさい クロヴィス兄様
Forgive me, Clovis.
ゼロに会ったんですけど
仇 取れませんでした
I met Zero, but I didn't avenge you.
でも ルルーシュやナナリーを
救う方法も思いつかなくて
But I couldn't think of any way
to save Lelouch and Nunnally.
私には
I don't have the power of big sister or Schneizel.
お姉様やシュナイゼル兄様のような
力は ありません
どこへ行っても足手まといで
No matter where I go,
I'm just a burden,
気がついたら わがままばかり
and I end up behaving
selfishly before I notice it myself.
お姉様に逆らって
騎士を選んでみたのですが…
I chose my knight against
big sister's advice.
返されちゃいました
And now he's resigned from that role.
ああ 聞いてはいるけど
今日は書類手続きだけで いいよね？
Oh yeah, they told me about you.
You just have to get the documents signed today.
中は皇族の方が ご観覧中で
A member of the royal family is
viewing the art inside right now.
え？　どなたですか？
Who is it?
え～ そらつまり…
Um, so you're saying?
澤崎とは合流しない
We aren't going to
collaborate with Sawasaki.
あれは独立ではなく かいらい政府だ
That's a puppet government, not an
independent one. The Chinese Federation's.
中華連邦のな
しかし日本を名乗っている
But they claim to be Japanese!
名前と主君が変わるだけ　未来はない
You'd just be changing names and masters.
There's no future with them.
無視するべきだ　あの日本を
We have to ignore this "Japan" of theirs.
ふ～ん　でもさあ それって…
Oh?
Then are you saying we don't interfere
with what the Britannians are doing?
ブリタニアの行動も放っておくのか？
ゼロ　組織としての方針を
明確にしておいた方が
Zero, perhaps you'd better clarify
what our organization's policy is.
そうだな
He's right.
澤崎の件はおいておくとしても
当面の目的ぐらいは
Even leaving the Sawasaki matter
aside, what's our main objective here?
トウキョウに独立国を作る
To make Tokyo an independent nation!
え？
独立？
Independent?!
国を？
A nation?!
本気か？
Are you serious?!
俺達の？
Us?
国って…
A country?
あ…
なるほど　やはり あなたは…
I thought so. You really are!
待ってくれ！
Hold on! No matter how big the
Black Knights have gotten!
いくら黒の騎士団が
大きくなったといっても…
敵は世界の３分の１以上を占める大国
The enemy is a nation that
controls a third of the entire world!
俺達だけで そんな事を？
We can't pull that off ourselves!
では聞こう！
Then answer me this!
お前達は 誰かがブリタニアを
倒してくれるのを待つつもりか？
Who are you waiting for to beat Britannia?
誰かが自分の代わりにやってくれる
Is someone going to do it for you?
待っていれば いつかはチャンスが来る
You think if you wait long enough,
some day the chance will come?
甘えるな！
Don't be naive!
自らが動かない限り
そんないつかは絶対に来ない！
If we don't do it,
that "some day" will never come!
ユーフェミア様！
Princess Euphemia!
あ！
あ？
周辺確認
- Secure the perimeter! Case Delta! We have a Case Delta!
ケースデルタ発生　ケースデルタ発生
- Please! I just want to thank Princess Euphemia!
- Secure the perimeter! Case Delta! We have a Case Delta!
ユーフェミア様に
お礼を言いたいだけなの
- Please! I just want to thank Princess Euphemia!
- This is front gate! Emergency lock down! Lock down all entrances!
一目だけでも…
- Just one look at her!
- This is front gate! Emergency lock down! Lock down all entrances!
- I say again, lock down all gates leading into the building!
ああ…
あ！
ホテルの…
From the hotel!
お願い… お願い…
Please! Please!
コースルームを開けておけ　連行する
Open fourth room! We're moving through.
おやめなさい！
Stop it! That girl's a friend of mine!
彼女は わたくしの友人です
あ！
よし 上がったな
Good. It's cleared up.
これで上陸作戦を再開できます
Now we can retry the landing operation.
シュナイゼル殿下のご提案も
実行できるかと
And we'll try to make Prince
Schneizel's proposal work.
特派は突破できると思うか？
You think A.S.E.E.C.
will be able to break through?
枢木ならば あるいは
With Kururugi, it's possible.
ふ 扱いに困る男だ
Using him may be trouble.
しかし指揮官がいない船です
技術力だけでは…
Still, there's no commander aboard that ship.
It's just a question of technology.
ミサイル接近
Incoming missiles!
Apparent launch point: Fukuoka base!
フクオカ基地から発射されたもよう
着弾まで1分05秒
1 minute, 5 seconds to impact!
さすがぁ
空爆対策もしっかりしてるねぇ
Not bad! They're well-prepared
against air attack as well.
弾幕を張りますか？
Are we laying down a barrage?
この位置なら大丈夫よ
We're fine where we are.
着弾確認！　敵航空艦 撃破！
Impacts confirmed!
Enemy flying carrier, destroyed!
ふんっ
いくら最新型であろうと 単艦では
Even if it is the latest model,
a single ship can't beat us!
ん？
これは…
What the?!
ランスロットで実証済みだからねぇ
We proved this system was
practical with the Lancelot, after all.
枢木少佐 作戦概要を再度確認します
Maj. Kururugi, just to reconfirm
the mission outline,
当艦は高高度から敵の前線を突破し
発艦ポイントまで移動中
This ship will breach the enemy's front line at
high altitude and move to your launch point.
嚮導兵器Z-01ランスロットは
フロートユニットを使用し
The advanced prototype weapon
Z- 01 Lancelot, using the float unit,
敵司令部 フクオカ基地を強襲せよ
will attack the enemy headquarters at Fukuoka base.
なお フロートは
エナジー消費が激しい為
Further, the float unit consumes
energy at a high rate,
稼働時間に留意
so pay attention to your operational time limit!
イエス マイ・ロード
Yes, My Lord.
ＭＥブースト
M.E. boost.
ランスロット 発艦！
Lancelot, launch!
発艦！
Launching!
敵艦から爆撃機が発艦したようですが
速度が戦闘機以上です
The enemy ship seems to have launched a
bomber, but it's faster than a fighter plane!
映像を捉えます
I have video!
おお…
ナイトメア
A Knightmare!
空輸ではなく 単独飛行だと？
Not being transported,
but flying on its own?!
まさか 報告にあった…
Could it be what was reported?
あの機装兵器か！
That fantastic weapon?!
では あれには…
Then, piloting it is!
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
キュウシュウブロックを
占拠しようとしてる連中の大義名分は
The group occupying the Kyushu
block is fighting for Atsushi Sawasaki.
澤崎敦の存在
つまり彼を失えば 新日本政府は瓦解
In short, if they lose him, the new
Japanese government will collapse.
中華連邦も介入の口実を失って
撤退せざるを得ないよね
And if the Chinese Federation loses their
excuse to be here, they'll have to withdraw.
あれが
There it is. The enemy headquarters.
敵の司令部
あ！
オープンチャンネル？
An open channel!
私は澤崎だ　こちらに向かってくる君は
枢木の息子か？
This is Sawasaki. Is that
Kururugi's son approaching here?
ん…
そうか こんな子供がいたのか
I see. So, that's the sort of son he had.
あの時…
That time... When you saved
me, Princess Euphemia...
ユーフェミア様が私を助けてくれた時
女神様に見えたんです
I saw a goddess.
It was like you glowed with light.
光り輝いていて まるで…
あっ　すみません
Forgive me! I should thank you
for this change of clothes!
服を貸して頂いたお礼から
言うべきでした
そんな事 気にしないで
Don't worry about that.
それにね… わたくしは
そんな立派な人間じゃないわ
Besides, I'm not at all the
wonderful person you think I am.
姉達に比べたら全然駄目で
I'm no good compared
to my brother and sister...
駄目じゃありません！
That's not true!
あ…
ユーフェミア様が駄目だなんて…
Saying that you're no good...
私なんか いいところ１つもなくって…
There's not one good thing about me...
Really, nothing at all.
本当に何も…
両親だって ただの人で
全然きれいじゃないし…
My parents are ordinary,
I'm not pretty at all...
そんな事ないわ
That's not true.
I think you're very sweet.
あなた とってもかわいいのに
あ…
そんな…
No...
ホントに駄目なんです　全然…
I'm no good. Not at all.
あ…
嫌いなのね 自分の事が…
She hates herself. But, so do I...
でも 私だって…
頭では分かっていても…
スザク君の事だって
And even though I understand
I shouldn't, when I think of Suzaku, I...
あ！　そうか スザクも！
I see. Suzaku, too!
だから ユーフェミア様が自分を
駄目だなんて言うのは やめてください
So please, don't say that you're
no good, Princess Euphemia!
だって　だって…
Because! Because...
だって 必要なんです　私にとって…
Because, I need you...
ありがとう ニーナ
あなたに会えて良かったわ
Thank you, Nina. I'm glad I met you.
あ！
なんか分かっちゃった！
I've learned something!
父は関係ありません
自分は戦いを終わらせる為に来ました
This has nothing to do with my
father. I came to end this fighting.
降伏さえして頂ければ
If you'll just surrender...
君は日本独立の夢を奪う気か
You intend to rob Japan of
its dream of independence?
なら正しい手段で叶えるべきです
Then make it happen the right way!
君はそうやって わがままを通すのか
You think doing that excuses your selfishness?
Is that your idea of justice without ideology?
理念なき正義だな
あ… 違います　それは…
You're wrong! l...
ぐあっ！
ヴァリスが…
My V.A.R.I.S.!
くっ…
あれが中華連邦のガン・ルゥ
That's a Chinese Federation Gun-Ru?
ふふふ
会話だけで気をそらすとは
まだまだ青い
He was distracted just from my talking to him.
He still has much to learn!
あ…
ユフィ？
Euphy?
シュナイゼル兄様
プライベート通信の許可を下さい！
Schneizel! Please let me make
a private communication!
くっ エナジーフィラーが…
Damn! My energy filler!
ああ？
フロートまで壊れたってぇ？
What?! The floater's broken, too?!
このアヴァロンを直接基地に！
We need to attack the
base directly with the Avalon!
無理無理
It won't work! The shield doesn't completely
surround us! We'll be shot down!
全方位シールドじゃないんだから
こっちが落とされちゃうよ
スザク君
エナジーを戦闘と通信に絞り込んで
Suzaku! Reroute all power to
combat and comms systems!
はい
Right!
投降したまえ スザク君
枢木玄武首相の遺児として
Give up, Suzaku!
As you're Prime Minister Kururugi's son,
I guarantee you'll be well-treated.
丁重に扱う事を約束するよ？
お断りします
Forget it. If I use my father's name for this,
I'll never be able to forgive myself!
ここで父の名を使ったら
もう 自分を許す事ができない
そうか　似ているなぁ 君は
強情なところが父親そっくりだよ
I see. You're very much your father's son.
You're just as stubborn as he was!
く…
枢木スザク！
Suzaku Kururugi!
え？
ユーフェミア様？
Princess Euphemia.
スザク
Suzaku! The truth is, I...
Um, you...
わたくしは あなたを
え～っと…
あの… 今は…
Pardon, but right now...
え～っと…
You see...
わたくしを好きになりなさい！
I demand that you love me!
はい！
Right!
え？
は？
何？　今度は何？
What?! Now what?!
あ いえ… プライベートでして
Um, sorry, this is private.
その代わり わたくしが
あなたを大好きになります！
And in return, I will love you!
ユーフェミア様…
Princess Euphemia...
スザク　あなたの頑ななところも
優しいところも
Suzaku, I love your stubbornness
and your kindness.
悲しそうな瞳も 不器用なところも
猫に噛まれちゃうところも全部！
Your sad eyes, your clumsiness,
the way you have trouble with cats...
I love everything about you!
だから自分を嫌わないで！
So please, don't hate yourself!
あ…
そうか…
かえって心配させちゃったんですね
I see. I only made
you worry more, didn't I?
あなたって人は！
You really are...
Everything you do is spur of the moment!
いつも いきなりです
出会った時も 皇女だって名乗った時も
When we first met, when you
announced you were a princess,
学校を決める時も僕を騎士に選んだ時も
when you decided on my school,
when you made me a knight... Always!
いつだって…
そうです いきなりです
Yes, all so sudden.
Because... I suddenly realize...
いきなり… 気づいちゃったんですから
でも そのいきなりのたびに
僕は扉を開けられた気がする
But, it's that unpredictability
that's opened doors for me.
ありがとう
Thank you!
何をしている！　奴を止めろ！
What are you doing?!
Stop him!
最後に お願いをしてもいいですか？
May I ask one final request?
最後？
Final?
僕に何かあっても
自分を嫌いにならないで下さい
Even if something happens to me,
please don't hate yourself.
あと その時は
僕の存在を全て消してもらえると
And then erase all traces
of what happened to me.
友達に迷惑はかけたくないから
転校した事にでもして下さい
I don't want my friends to be sad.
Just tell them I transferred or something.
スザク まさか…
Suzaku, don't tell me you're!
もう エナジーが尽きました
I've run out of energy.
ああ いけない
Oh, sorry. Say goodbye to Miss Cécile and
Mr. Lloyd and Prince Schneizel for me.
セシルさんやロイドさん
それとシュナイゼル殿下によろしく
あは…
最後まで独りよがりだったな　僕は…
Selfish to the very end, huh?
スザク 死なないで！　生きていて！
Suzaku, don't die! You must live!
あ… な… なんだ？
Wh-What the?
撃てえー！
FIRE!
あ…
なんだ 今のは？
What was that just now?!
レーダーに反応 いきなり現れました！
Something just appeared on radar!
ステルスか？
A stealth system?!
映像 捉えました！
We've got video!
あっ あれは…
That's!
あの白兜
ランスロットとかいう名前だったか？
So, the white helmet's
name is Lancelot?
相変わらず無茶な戦い方だな
It fights as recklessly
as ever, doesn't it?
ああ
Yes, but this time he seems
to have some backup.
しかし今回はバックがいるようだ
単機で本陣を撹乱しイレギュラーを作る
Sending a single fighter in to disrupt
the main force and surprise them.
失敗してもコーネリアは動きやすい
Even if he failed,
Cornelia can move in easily.
この策 シュナイゼルか？
Schneizel, did you come up
with this plan?
邪魔なんだよ 君達は
You people are just
getting in my way!
ハドロン砲は未完成のはずじゃあ…
I thought the Hadron
Cannon wasn't perfected!
集束できてる？
He can converge the beams?!
くふふ
僕が完成させるはずだったのにぃ…
But I wanted to be the one to perfect it!
う～ん ゲフィオンディスターバーの
応用で なんとかなったな
Mm... Looks like utilizing the
Gefjun Disturber has worked.
でもフロートシステムの開発は
私の負け
But that float system has me beat.
やっぱり相手はプリン伯爵か？
My opponent must be
the Earl of Pudding.
思わぬ共同作業ね
We were collaborating
without realizing it. How distasteful.
あ～ 気持ち悪い
枢木よ　ランスロットは まだ動くか？
Kururugi, is Lancelot still operational?
やはり ゼロか？
Zero. I thought so.
ゼロだと？
Zero?
オープンチャンネルだな？
Is that an open channel?!
はい！
Yes, sir!
音を拾え！　目的を確認する！
Trace it! Confirm the target!
エナジーフィラー？
An energy filler?
私は今から敵の司令部を叩く
I'm going to take out the enemy H.Q.
What will you do?
君は どうする？
何？
What?!
ふっ
残念だけど ゼロ
お前の願いは叶わない
Sorry Zero,
but you're not getting your wish.
自分が先に叩かせてもらうよ
I'm going in to hit them first.
全て出せ！　止めるんだ！
Send everything out!
Stop them! Stop Kururugi and Zero!
ゼロと枢木を！
ゼロ！
Zero! Don't you fight for
those who grieve for Japan?!
お前達は日本を憂いる
同志ではないのか？
我ら黒の騎士団は
不当な暴力をふるう者 全ての敵だ
We Black Knights stand against
anyone who uses violence unjustly!
不当だと？　私は日本の為に！
Unjust?! I'm doing this for Japan!
澤崎さん！　日本の為なら
どうして中華連邦に逃げたんです！
Sawasaki! If this is for Japan, why did
you run away to the Chinese Federation?!
残るべきだった　みんなの為にも
You needed to stay,
for everyone's sake!
子供がぁ！
You child!
共同作戦か
A joint operation. The Gawain...
ガウェインと…
ランスロットの…
...and Lancelot.
スザクとルルーシュが…
Suzaku and Lelouch are!
何？　ゼロが？
What?! Zero is?!
はい　枢木と共に
Yes, along with Kururugi.
何を考えている？　あの男
What the hell is that man thinking?!
ブリタニアから逃れる為にも
It was right to send out the Gawain alone in
order to escape from the Britannians, wasn't it?
ガウェイン単独での作戦は
正解でしたね
でも…
Still, it would have been easier to
let the Guren act as a wall for them.
紅蓮が壁になれば もっと楽に…
どうせ私は
もう家にも学校にも帰れないし
It's not like I can go home or
back to school at this point.
今さらランスロットなんかと
手を組まなくたって…
After everything, to be working
with the Lancelot is just...
必要な事は勝利ではありません
What's necessary here isn't victory.
え？
この戦いに
黒の騎士団が参加したという事実です
The Black Knights' participation in
this operation is an undeniable truth.
無論　表立っての報道は
なされないでしょうが 噂は流せます
Of course, it won't be officially
reported, but rumors will spread.
ゼロが言う通り これは私達の立場を
全世界に伝える役に立つでしょう
As Zero said, this will tell
the world about our position.
外国に助力を乞い機会を待って何が悪い
What's wrong with going to a foreign country
for help and then waiting for a chance?!
それこそが戦略というものなのに
That's what's called strategy, isn't it?
カゴシマなら まだ防衛線が引けますよ？
We can still set up a defense line at Kagoshima.
は 世話になります
Right. I appreciate your help.
え？
ああ！
おお！
澤崎さん
Sawasaki!
ここまでだな
That's as far as you go.
バ… バカな…
Impossible! The largest fortress in
Kyushu, with hardly any effort!
キュウシュウ最大の要凱を
いとも簡単に…
キュウシュウブロックで勃発した
反体制組織によるテロ事件は
The terrorist action in Kyushu block led
by an anti-government terror group...
コーネリア総督の電撃作戦により
was put down by Princess
Cornelia's lightning attack,
澤崎敦 以下４名の
旧日本政府メンバーを確保
resulting in the capture of Atsushi Sawasaki and
four members of the old Japanese government.
関与した中華連邦軍の半数以上を
捕虜としました
Over half of the Chinese Federation troops
assisting them were captured as well.
なお 中華連邦首脳部は
今回の件に関して
In response to this incident,
Chinese Federation leaders...
両島軍管区 ツァオ将軍の
独断であるとの姿勢を崩しておらず
claim the operation
was an unauthorized action...
by Luogong military district
commander Gen. Tsao.
チベット条約に基づく
捕虜の返還を要求してきています
He is requesting the return of P.O.W.'s
under the articles of the Tibet Convention.
枢木スザク ただいま帰還しました
Suzaku Kururugi, returning for duty.
お帰りなさい スザク
Welcome back, Suzaku.
あ…
うふ
あの！
Um!
え…
あ…
うふ
あ ああ
ふふふ…
スザク
Suzaku, I finally understand.
私ね 分かったんです
理想の国家とか大義とか
そういう難しい事じゃなくて
It's not that I want an ideal country or great
justice or anything complicated like that.
ただ私は笑顔が見たいんだって
I just want to see people smiling.
今 大好きな人と
かつて大好きだった人の笑顔が
The smiles of the people I love now
and those of the ones I loved before.
私を… 手伝ってくれますか？
Will you help me with this?
イエス ユア・ハイネス
Yes, Your Highness.
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
意味もなく繰り返し
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
過去の嘘も過ちも
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
澤崎を潰した以上
次の行動は迅速になさねばならない
Now that Sawasaki's been stopped,
we have to make our next move quickly!
ナナリーの居場所を最優先に構築する
Building a place where
Nunnally can live her life well.
その為にも
世界の楔となるべき国を作りだす
And for that, I need to create a nation
to drive a wedge into the world.
破壊への仕込みは順調に進んでいる
Things are proceeding well
towards destruction.
時が来れば コーネリアとシュナイゼル
And when the time comes,
I'll face down Cornelia and Schneizel directly!
２人まとめて…
THE SCHOOL FESTIVAL DECLARATION